The only thing more dangerous than the mission is the escape.
Kandahar is a action, thriller, war film directed by Ric Roman Waugh.
After his mission is exposed, an undercover CIA operative stuck deep in hostile territory in Afghanistan must fight his way out, alongside his Afghan
translator, to an extraction point in Kandahar, all whilst avoiding elite enemy forces and foreign spies tasked with hunting them down.
Tom Harris, played by Gerard Butler.
Mohammad 'Mo' Doud, played by Navid Negahban.
Roman Chalmers, played by Travis Fimmel.
Kahil Nasir, played by Ali Fazal.
Farzad Asadi, played by Bahador Foladi.
Luna Cujai, played by Nina Toussaint-White.
Kandahar, titled Mission Kandahar in Canada, is a 2023 American spy action thriller
film directed by Ric Roman Waugh and written by Mitchell LaFortune.
The film stars Gerard Butler (who is also a producer) and features a supporting cast that includes Ali Fazal, Navid Negahban, Bahador
Foladi, Nina Toussaint-White, Tom Rhys Harries, Vassilis Koukalani, Mark Arnold, Corey Johnson, and Travis Fimmel.
Loosely based on actual events, the story follows a CIA operative and his
translator who flee Afghanistan after their covert mission is exposed.
The film was released in theaters on May 26, 2023 by Open Road Films.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency
(cia), undercover agent, behind enemy lines.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.